FORREST MILLS

San Antonio, TX

Phone: 830-928-6232 | Email: mills_forrest@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/forrest-mills-dev | GitHub: https://github.com/fmills89 | Portfolio: https://fmills89.github.io/my-react-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with experience in agile environments and the ability to create capable, reliable, and mobile-first applications. Understand processes and assisted in both front and back-end development for collective effort projects. Aim to problem-solve and work as a team to achieve goals effectively.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, HTML, CSS, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Rest APIs, Mongoose.js, Express.js, jQuery, GraphQL, MERN Stack, MySQL, Jest.js, Tailwind.css, Bulma **Applications:** npm, Heroku, MongoDB Atlas, Github

PROJECTS

Pokemon-Teams | https://github.com/fmills89/poke-teams-builder

l https://evening-mountain-59213.herokuapp.com

- Group effort to build a responsive and mobile-friendly website where registered users can create and edit a team of pokemon.
- Managed and provided front-end UI/UX design. Assisted with hooking front to back-end.
- Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, React, Express, Node, Apollo, GraphQL, Heroku

One-Stop-Shop | https://github.com/fmills89/one-stop-shop

I https://group1-one-stop-shop.herokuapp.com

- Second group project where users can sign up and grocery shop online.
- Managed connecting front to REST APIs, created login page and assisted with creating Handlebars.js components. Server and Config creation.
- Bootstrap, Handlebars, Express, Javascript, Node, MySQL, Heroku

Brew-Me | https://github.com/fmills89/brew-me

I https://iessebubble.github.io/brew-me/

- Through group collaboration, Brew-Me is a website where you can search for local breweries.
- Provided implementation of Mapbox API and integrated it with the Brewery API to locate breweries based on user input.
- Tailwind CSS, Javascript, HTML, Mapbox API, Brewery API

EXPERIENCE

RSC Rep IV 2016 – 2021

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

Coordinated and managed quota moves to meet service level agreements.

- Formulated quota reports, move reports, and forecasted connect activity based on demand, special projects, and marketing forecasts.
- Managed field operations scheduling and workforce management.
- Managed the creation and maintenance of technical skill sets.

Dispatcher V

2015 - 2016

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

- Managed and dispatched teams of technicians and ensured timeframes were met. Moved work between teams of technicians.
- Provided technical support via phone for all residential services.
- Processed, scheduled, and corrected work orders.

Technical Support Rep II 20

2014 - 2015

Charter Communications

San Antonio, TX

- Provided customer care and technical support for all residential services.
- Managed de-escalation of customer escalations.

Technical Support Rep II

2014 - 2014

Volt

San Antonio, TX

- Provided customer care & technical support for all residential services.
- Diagnosed chronic issues, created escalation tickets, and followed up on final resolutions.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of Texas at San Antonio, San Antonio, TX A 24-week intensive program focused on developing technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MERN, MVC Model, OOP, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

A.S. of Science: Northeast Lakeview College, San Antonio, TX 2018 - 2023